So, let's start with one classification example.
それでは分類の例を見ていきましょう
Let's say we are the admissions office at
大学の入学事務局員として
a university and our job is to accept or reject students.
新しい学生の合否を決める職務に就いているとしましょう
So, in order to evaluate students,
学生を評価するための
we have two pieces of information,
2つの情報があるとします
the results of a test and their grades in school.
テストの結果と学校の成績です
So, let's take a look at some sample students.
何人かの学生の情報を例としてみてみましょう
We'll start with Student 1 who got 9 out of 10 in the test and 8 out of 10 in the grades.
まずは テストは10点中9点 成績は10点中8点の学生1を見てみます
That student did quite well and got accepted.
学生1は優秀な点数を取ったため大学に合格しました
Then we have Student 2 who got 3 out of 10 in the test and 4 out of 10 in the grades,
続いて テストは10点中3点 成績は10点中4点の学生2がいます
and that student got rejected.
学生2は不合格になりました
And now, we have a new Student 3 who got 7 out of
さらに テストは10点中7点
10 in the test and 6 out of 10 in the grades,
成績は10点中6点の学生3がいるとします
and we're wondering if the student gets accepted or not.
さて 学生3は大学に合格するでしょうか
So, our first way to find this out is to plot students in a graph with
この問題を解く最初の手順として
the horizontal axis corresponding to the score on
テストの点数を水平軸で表し
the test and the vertical axis corresponding to the grades,
成績を垂直軸で表したグラフで学生の情報を見てみましょう
and the students would fit here.
学生はこのようにグラフの点で表されます
The students who got three and four gets located in the point with coordinates (3,4),
3点と4点を取得した学生は座標(3,4)の点
and the student who got nine and eight gets located in the point with coordinates (9,8).
9点と8点を取得した学生は座標(9,8)の点で表されています
And now we'll do what we do in most of our algorithms,
アルゴリズムを使用する際によく行われる手順として
which is to look at the previous data.
過去のデータを見てみましょう
This is how the previous data looks.
これが過去のデータです
These are all the previous students who got accepted or rejected.
これまでに合格または不合格になったすべての学生のデータです
The blue points correspond to students that got accepted,
青い点は合格した学生を示し
and the red points to students that got rejected.
赤い点は不合格となった学生を表しています
So we can see in this diagram that the students would did
このグラフをみると テストの点数と成績が高かった学生は合格率が高く
well in the test and grades are more likely to get accepted,
どちらの点数も比較的低かった学生は
and the students who did poorly in both are more likely to get rejected.
合格率も低いということがわかります
So let's start with a quiz.
それでは問題です
The quiz says, does the Student 3 get accepted or rejected?
学生3は合格するでしょうか? それとも不合格でしょうか?
What do you think? Enter your answer below.
どう思いますか?ここに回答を入力してください